Our assassination plan went so well
僕らの暗殺計画がいいところまでいってしまったせいで
殺せんせーは完全防御形態になってしまった
that Korosensei wound up in his Absolute Defense Form.
そんな中　起こった事件
Then all this happened.
殺せんせーに頼ることはできない
We can't rely on Korosensei for help.
僕らだけで　犯人からワクチンを奪わなくちゃならない
We have to steal the remedy from the bad guys... alone.
患者１０人と看病に残した２人を除き
Not counting the ten patients and the two left behind to care for them,
動ける生徒全員でここから侵入
all capable students must sneak in from here,
最上階を奇襲して　治療薬を奪い取るのです
get the jump on the guys at the top,
and steal that remedy!
It's too dangerous.
危険過ぎる
この手慣れた脅迫の手口
The ease with which he threatened us shows we're up against a real pro.
敵は明らかにプロのものだぞ
Yes. Perhaps it would be wisest simply to hand me over.
ええ　おとなしく私を渡した方が得策かもしれません
どうしますか
What do you think?
It's up to all of you.
あなた方しだいです
これは…　ちょっと…
But... This is...
It's too hard.
難しいだろ
ホテルにたどりつく前に転落死よ
They'll plummet to their deaths before they get anywhere near the hotel.
やはり無理だ
I knew it. It's no use.
２人に持っていかせるしか…
We have to send him with those two.
渚君　茅野さん　すまないが…
Nagisa-kun, Kayano-san.
I'm sorry, but—
いやまあ　崖だけなら　楽勝だけどさ
Well, if you're worried about the rock climbing,
that much is a piece of cake.
It's nothing compared to our usual training.
いつもの特訓に比べたらね
だね
Right?
でも　未知のホテルで未知の敵と戦う訓練はしてないから
But we haven't practiced fighting an unknown foe in an unknown hotel,
烏間先生
so, Karasuma-sensei...
It won't be easy, but could you lead our mission?
難しいけど　指揮　頼みます
ふざけたまねしたやつらに　きっちり落とし前つけてやる
We'll make that jerk pay for messin' with us!
見てのとおり　彼らはただの生徒ではない
As you can see, they're no ordinary students.
あなたの元には　１５人の特殊部隊がいるのですよ
You have a fifteen-member special forces unit at your command.
１５人
Fifteen?
Don't forget about me!
私を忘れないでくださいね
Now, there's not much time.
さあ　時間はないですよ
全員注目
Attention!
Our objective is the top floor of the hotel at the summit!
われわれの目標は山頂ホテル最上階
隠密潜入から奇襲への連続ミッションだ
Our mission will shift from a stealth infiltration to a surprise attack!
ハンドサインや連携については　訓練のものをそのまま使う
We'll use the same hand signals and link-ups from training!
The only difference is our target!
いつもと違うのはターゲットのみ
You have three minutes to memorize the map.
３分でマップをたたき込め
２１５０　作戦開始
We begin at 2150!
Right!
おう
Stand, bow, lock on!
kiritsu rei lock on
起立
礼
ロックオン
起立
Stand, bow, lock on!
kiritsu rei lock on
礼
ロックオン
Oh yeah!
oh yeah
The target is our teacher!
sensei target on
せんせー
ターゲットオン
总监.Maki
台本.小伍
ポテンシャル高い
总监.Maki
台本.小伍
We've got a lot of potential
potential takai
ポテンシャル高い
ほどめんどくさい
It's just that we're not trying
hodo mendokusai
ほどめんどくさい
总监.Maki
台本.小伍
ほどめんどくさい
We had that dropouts' mentality
dropout mentality
ほどめんどくさい
ドロップアウト　メンタリティー
No matter the unusual situation we were in
hinichijou wo ryougashi
翻译.兰樱
非日常を凌駕し
校对.Maki
翻译.兰樱
非日常を凌駕し
校对.Maki
僕らはうたたね顔して
时间轴.歪歪
BDRip.VCB-Studio
We pretended to doze off
bokura wa utatanegao shite
僕らはうたたね顔して
时间轴.歪歪
BDRip.VCB-Studio
僕らはうたたね顔して
While holding on to a hidden knife
knife kakushimotta
时间轴.歪歪
BDRip.VCB-Studio
僕らはうたたね顔して
时间轴.歪歪
BDRip.VCB-Studio
ナイフ隠し持った
起立
Stand, bow, lock on!
kiritsu rei lock on
礼
ロックオン
Thinking someone would deal with you eventually
hottokeba kitto dareka yatte kureru to
ほっとけば　きっと誰か　やってくれると
We didn't really feel invested in the job
doko ka taningoto datta
どこか　他人事だった
だけど
But now
dakedo
だけど
Teacher, teach us, we're still growing up
mister teacher oshiete mikansei na bokura
Mr.ティーチャー教えて　未完成の僕ら
あなたという不落のターゲット　撃抜けるでしょうか
Will we be able to shoot through an invincible target like you?
anata to iu furaku no target uchinukeru deshou ka
あなたという不落のターゲット　撃抜けるでしょうか
As long as we challenge you, it's fifty-fifty
Stand, bow, lock on!
idomu kagiri kanousei wa half and half
kiritsu rei lock on
挑む限り　可能性はハーフ＆ハーフ
Teacher, watch us, as we try to find a direction in life
mister teacher mite ite mayoi ooki bokura
Mr.ティーチャー見ていて　迷い多き僕ら
誰よりもあなたのために猛勉強中さ
We're studying our ass off for you more than anybody else
dare yori mo anata no tame ni moubenkyouchuu sa
誰よりもあなたのために猛勉強中さ
殺意だけが　あなたへのメッセージ
Only the bloodlust is our message to you
satsui dake ga anata e no message
Stand, bow, lock on! Stand, bow, lock on!
kiritsu rei lock on kiritsu rei lock on
殺意だけが　あなたへのメッセージ
自力　ガチで
We'll make our dreams come true on our own for real
jiriki gachi de hongan iku yo
自力　ガチで
本願　行くよ
A revolution!
revolution
レボリューション
Oh yeah!
oh yeah
せんせー
The target is our teacher!
sensei target on
せんせー
ターゲットオン
Episode
Pandemonium
Time
本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流，禁止用于商业用途
更多中日双语字幕，尽在 i.kamigami.org 及微博 @诸神字幕组
Fifty... minutes left...
あと…
５０分
Don't get left behind!
置いてくよ
やっぱ　身軽だな　岡野は
Okano sure can move.
Yeah. She's got the rest of us beat when it comes to gymnastics.
ああ　こういうことやらせたら　クラス１だ
それに比べて　うちの先生は…
On the other hand, with our teachers...
One guy has to carry the rest. Literally.
動けるのが３人中１人とは…
Too shaky! Climb more carefully! Ugh!
もっと静かに登りなさいよ　烏間
Karasuma!
The students all have exceptional balance.
しかし　皆さん　見事なバランス感覚ですね
クライミングなら　学校の裏山でもさせている
I have them climb the mountain behind the school.
I see. No wonder they had those flyboards down pat.
なるほど
フライボードを自在に操ったのもその成果ですね
Shut up and climb already!
いいから早く登んなさいよ　手が疲れてきたわ
My hands are getting tired!
Why did Bitch-sensei come again?
つーか　ビッチ先生　何でついてきてんだ
留守番とか　のけ者みたいで　嫌なんだって
She didn't want to be left out.
I wouldn't mind... if she wasn't such a dead weight.
足手まといにならなきゃいいけどな
業君　待って
Karma-kun, wait!
待ってあげたいけど
I'd like to, but we're kind of on a schedule here.
タイムリミットがあるでしょ
そうだね
You're right.
Let's do this!
行こう
Mind the sharp rock.
その岩　とがってるよ
Huh?
Oh, that was close.
危なかったぁ
Make it snappy!
ねえ　ちょっと早くしてよ　腕に筋肉ついちゃうじゃない
What, are those biceps just for show?
でも　殺せんせーのことを知っている犯人って
Still...
If this guy knows about Korosensei, who could he be?
何者なんだ
Ritsu, run a final check of our invasion route.
律　侵入ルートの最終確認だ
Yes, sir. Displaying interior map.
はい　内部マップを表示します
最終確認です
Final check:
We can't use the elevators, as they require a passcard for every floor.
私たちはエレベーターを使用できません
各階ごとの専用ＩＣカードが必要だからです
We'll have to take the stairs,
従って　階段を上るしかないのですが
but they're scattered throughout the hotel,
その階段も　ばらばらに配置されており
so we'll have to cover some distance on foot.
長い距離を歩かなくてはなりません
It's like a TV station.
テレビ局みたいな構造だな
どういうこと
What do you mean?
Apparently they have complex layouts to prevent a terrorist takeover.
テロリストに占拠されないように
複雑な設計になってるらしい
ああ…　詳しいんだね
You sure know a lot about it.
No wonder the bad guys love staying here.
こりゃあ　悪い宿泊客が愛用するわけだ
Unlocking side entrance.
通用口　ロック解除
Let's go. We're running out of time.
行くぞ　時間がない
はい
Yes, sir!
There are more guards than I expected.
予想以上に警備が多いな
It'd be too difficult for us all to get past.
全員が通過するのは難しいんじゃ…
Should only a few of us go on from here?
ここは　やはり　人数を絞って潜入するか…
No, the chance of facing multiple enemies makes it too risky.
いや　敵が複数だった場合　危険過ぎる
What should we do?
どうするべきか…
What's the holdup? Just go on through.
何よ　普通に通ればいいじゃない
Do you have any idea of the situation here, Bitch-sensei?
状況判断もできねえのかよ　ビッチ先生
あんだけの警備の中　どうやって
How are we supposed to make it past all those guards?
Just go through!
だから　普通によ
Grin.
I'm sorry.
ごめんなさい　部屋のお酒で悪酔いしちゃって
I seem to have had too much of the liquor in my room.
Oh, er, think nothing of it, miss.
お…お気になさらず　お客さま
I'm the pianist scheduled to perform here next week.
来週　そこでピアノを弾かせていただく者よ
早入りして観光してたの
I came early to see the sights.
A pianist, eh?
ピアニストか
しょっちゅう来るから　その一人だろ
We get 'em all the time.
I'd like to see if the piano's in tune. It'll help me sober up.
酔いざましにね　ピアノの調律をチェックしておきたいの
ちょっとだけ　弾かせてもらっていいかしら
Could I play a teensy little bit, hmm?
Well, uh... Let me check with the front—
えっと…　じゃあ　フロントに確認を
Aw, come on.
いいじゃない
I want you to hear me play.
あなたたちにも聴いてほしいの
そして審査して
And then critique me.
C-Critique you?
し…審査
Yes, critique me carefully...
そう　私のこと　よーく審査して
and if I do anything wrong, will you scold me?
駄目なとこがあったら　叱ってくださる
め…
She's...
She's freakin' amazing!
めちゃめちゃ上手だ
Ah, the Fantaisie-Impromptu.
『幻想即興曲』ですね
An assassin who not only has obvious skill,
but also knows all too well
腕前もさることながら　見せ方が実にお見事
how to charm, how to use her wiles...
色気の見せ方を熟知した暗殺者が
全身をあでやかに使って音を奏でる
Using her whole body in such a bewitching way as she plays:
まさに　音色
it's aural seduction!
All eyes are on her.
どんな視線も引き付けてしまう
C'mon, don't watch from so far away.
ねえ　そんな遠くで見てないで
Come closer and make sure I do well.
もっと近くで　確かめて
お…おお…
I'll buy you twenty minutes. Go.
２０分稼いであげる　行きなさい
Even we were spellbound,
僕らまで思わず目を奪われた
thinking what a beautiful teacher we had.
なんて奇麗な先生なんだろうって…
We all made it through!
全員　無事に突破
すげえや　ビッチ先生
Isn't Bitch-sensei something?
あの爪でよくやるぜ
Playing like that with those nails?
ああ　ピアノ弾けるなんて一言も…
She never said anything about being able to play.
普段の彼女から甘く見ないことだ
There's more to her than what you see every day.
優れた殺し屋ほど　よろずに通じる
The better the assassin, the broader her skill set.
君らに会話術を教えているのは
The woman who's been teaching you conversation skills
世界でも　一二を争うハニートラップの達人なのだ
is amongst the top one or two masters of seduction in the world.
So my current immobility won't be a problem.
私が動けなくても　まったく心配ないですね
Let's go!
行こう
Uh-huh!
うん
やられるんじゃないわよ
Don't let them get the better of you.
Fukuma Denjo Hotel
Current Location
Display Route
All right.
さて　入り口の厳しいチェックさえ抜けてしまえば
CURRENT LOCATION
3rd Floor Corridor
Now that we're past the heavy security at the entrance,
we should be able to pose as regular guests.
ここからは　客のふりができる
客　こんな所に中学生の団体客なんているんですか
Guests? Do they put up groups of junior-high kids here?
Plenty, from what I've heard.
聞いたかぎり結構いる
芸能人や金持ち連中のぼんぼんたちだ
The coddled kids of millionaires and celebrities.
Brought up like decadent royalty,
王様のように甘やかされて育った彼らは
they keep innocent faces while dabbling in darker pursuits.
あどけない顔のうちから　悪い遊びに手を染める
Right! So walk around acting like those kids,
そう　だから君たちもそんなやからになったつもりで
世の中をなめてる感じで　歩いてみましょう
looking down your noses at the whole world!
Yes, that's the way!
そうそう　その調子
その調子…なのか
Is it, now?
And don't you join in!
あと　お前までなめるな
However, we have no idea what our opponent looks like.
ただし　われわれも敵の顔を知りません
敵もまた　客のふりで襲ってくるかもしれない
He might attack while posing as a regular guest like us.
十分に警戒して進みましょう
Proceed with plenty of caution.
ち～っす
Natch!
Sorry, Okuda... Takebayashi.
悪いな　奥田　竹林
I-It's okay.
い…いえ
みんな　発熱がひどい
Their fevers are so high.
脳にダメージがいかないよう
At the very least, we need to cool their heads down to avoid brain damage.
頭だけは冷やしておくんだ
は…はい
G-Got it.
あ…あのう　これだけ強いウイルスなら
Um... Could a virus this powerful spread throughout the island?
この島中に広まってしまうんじゃ…
Probably not. I mean, we're okay, right?
たぶんそれはない　僕らは無事じゃないか
これはおそらく経口感染
It's likely to be transmitted orally.
It'd have to be mixed into food or drink or something.
飲食物等に混入されたとみるべきだね
I doubt there's any risk of it spreading to a random bystander.
赤の他人にバシバシうつす心配はないと思う
I told the other team that, too.
あそこに行ったみんなにも　そう伝えたけど
A virus given to us and us alone...
私たちだけを狙って盛られたウイルス
But when? And where?
いったい　いつ　どこで…
Fukuma Denjo: Corridor to 3rd Floor Central Hall
CURRENT LOCATION
It really is like we're all just regular guests.
本当にただの客同士って感じだな
むしろ　視線を合わせない
If anything, they avoid eye contact.
トラブルを避けたいのは　あっちも一緒なんだろうな
No one wants to cause any trouble, after all.
I originally thought we'd have to take on everyone in the hotel,
ホテル内の全員が敵かと思ってたけど
これなら　最上階まですんなり行けそうだね
but it looks like we can just stroll up to the top floor.
And if something does happen...
仮に何かあっても　前衛の烏間先生が見つけてくれるよ
3rd Floor Central Hall
CURRENT LOCATION
our point man, Karasuma-sensei, is looking out for all of us.
入っちまえば楽勝じゃねえか
It'll be a cinch now that we're inside!
油断するな
Stay alert.
We don't have time to play around. Let's do this!
時間ねえんだから　さっさと進んだ方がいいだろう
おい
Hey!
Terasaka-kun! Watch out!
寺坂君　そいつ危ない
Gas?!
ガスか
Karasuma-sensei!
烏間先生
なぜ　分かった
How could you tell?
I kill in passing without the slightest hint of bloodlust.
殺気を見せず　擦れ違いざまやる
That happens to be my specialty, Helmet Hair.
俺のおはこだったんだがなぁ　おかっぱちゃん
Aren't you the man who gave us our welcome drinks?
だって　おじさん　最初にサービスドリンク配った人でしょ
Please enjoy this tropical juice with our compliments.
サービスのトロピカルジュースでございます
不破さん…
Fuwa-san!
It's downright fishy for someone like that to be walking around in here!
そんな人がここを歩いてるなんて
明らかに怪しいわ
確かに
She's right!
You've got a good eye.
よく見てるじゃないか
Then was it you who gave everyone that virus?
じゃあ　みんなにウイルスを盛ったのも…
That's a pretty flimsy accusation.
断定するには証拠が弱いぜ
There would have been plenty of other opportunities to slip you that stuff.
ドリンクじゃなくても　そんなものを盛る機会はたくさんあるだろう
The only time we all ate or drank the same thing
クラス全員が同じものを口にしたのは
was with those drinks and our shipboard dinner.
あのドリンクと船上でのディナーのときだけ
けど　ディナーを食べずに映像編集してた三村君と岡島君も感染したから
But Mimura-kun and Okajima-kun worked on the video right through dinner, and they're both sick,
which narrows it down to those daytime drinks.
感染源は昼間のドリンクに絞られる
And that means...
従って…
the culprit is you, mister!
犯人は　あなたよ　おじさん君
That's amazing, Fuwa-san!
すごいよ　不破さん
何か探偵みたい
You were just like a detective!
普段から　少年漫画読んでるとね
When you read a lot of shounen manga,
普通じゃない状況がきても　素早く適応できるのよ
you learn to adjust quickly to unusual situations.
Magazine and Sunday are
chock-full of detective manga hits!
特に　探偵物は『マガジン』『サンデー』ともに　メガヒット揃い
『ジャンプ』は
What about Jump?
Huh? Jump's detective stuff?
えっ　『ジャンプ』の探偵物
I don't really know, but they're putting out a compilation.
The solution to this mystery is already on the tip of my tongue.
この謎はもう吾輩の舌の上だ
よく知らないけど
文庫版が出てるらしいから　買うといいと思うよ
Better pick one up!
Neuro Nougami, the mystery-solving demon. Matsui Yuusei's debut title! 12 compilation volumes now available!
I get tortured nonstop!
私がひたすら拷問されます　そんな漫画です
That's the kind of manga this is.
いやらしいよ
That's nasty!
Be more subtle with the product placement, Fuwa-san!
ステマが露骨だよ　不破さん
もっとマーケティング倫理に配慮して
Pay more attention to ethics in marketing!
I guess even if you've found me out, it's already too late.
まあ　俺の正体が知れたところで　もう手遅れなんだがなぁ
A poisoner, eh?
毒物使い…ですか
And quite skilled in practical application.
しかも　実用性に優れている
My very own paralysis gas for indoor use.
俺特製の室内用麻酔ガスだ
One whiff can bring down an elephant.
一瞬吸えば象すら落とすし
Fresh air neutralizes it, leaving no evidence behind.
外気に触れればすぐ分解して証拠も残らん
Now, it's plain to see you have no intention of honoring our arrangement.
さて　お前たちに取引の意思がないことはよーく分かった
Negotiations have broken down.
交渉決裂　ボスに報告するとするか
Guess I'll have to tell my boss.
They're fast!
速い
When did they block the exits?!
いつの間に出口を…
When encountering an enemy...
敵と遭遇した場合…
即座に退路をふさぎ…
...immediately block their retreat path...
連絡を絶つ
...and cut off communications!
ですよね　烏間先生
Isn't that right, Karasuma-sensei?
お前は…　われわれを見た瞬間に攻撃せずに報告に帰るべきだったな
The minute you saw us,
you should've held off attacking
and gone back to tell your boss.
まだしゃべれるとは驚きだ
I'm surprised you can still talk.
But all you have left is a bunch of kids.
だが　しょせん　他はがきの集まり
お前が死ねば　統制がとれずに逃げだすだろうさ
Once you're dead,
they'll stop following orders and just run away!
S-So strong... And such inhuman speed...
つ…強え…
人間の速さじゃねえ…
だがな…　恐ろしい先生よ…
But y'know, Terrifying Teach...
your command...
お前の引率…　も…
ends... right... here!
ここ…　まで…　だ…
Ka—
か…
Karasuma-sensei!
烏間先生
You can't keep going like this, Karasuma-sensei.
これ以上は無理ですよ　烏間先生
I'll be fine in half an hour.
３０分で回復させる
Don't do anything crazy.
決して無茶はするな
He's the crazy one. That gas was supposed to stop an elephant in its tracks!
象も倒すガス浴びて歩ける方がおかしいって
Karasuma-sensei's kind of a monster himself.
烏間先生も十分化け物だよね
A pro with both experience and know-how is really something.
経験と知識を重ねたプロは本当にすごい
And that's the kind of pro waiting for us up ahead.
そんなプロがこの先も待ち構えている
Can we beat him with our power alone?
僕らの力だけで勝てるのか
Man, it sure is starting to feel like summer vacation, am I right?
いや～　いよいよ　夏休みって感じですねぇ
Well, aren't you happy-go-lucky!
何よ　お気楽な
Says the only one who's absolutely safe!
一人だけ　絶対安全な形態のくせに
Nagisa, twirl him around till he's sick!
渚　振り回して酔わせろ
Okay, Terasaka, I'm jamming him in. Drop trou and spread those cheeks!
よし　寺坂　これ　ねじ込むから
パンツ下ろしてケツ開いて
That'd kill me!
死ぬわ
Korosensei, why does this feel like summer?
殺せんせー　何でこれが夏休み
The teacher-student relationship isn't a cozy one.
先生と生徒はなれ合いではありません
Summer vacation fosters student independence in places beyond a teacher's protection.
そして　夏休みとは
先生の保護が及ばないところで　自立性を養う場でもあります
If you apply the lessons you've learned in your usual gym classes,
普段の体育で学んだことをしっかりやれば
there will be few enemies for you to fear.
そうそう恐れる敵はいない
This is your assassination vacation... and you can beat it.
君たちはクリアできます　この暗殺夏休みを
Start with a rich seafood stock.
濃厚な魚介だしに
Add plenty of green onions and a spoon of minced garlic...
たっぷりのネギとひとさじのニンニク
and a gun!
そして　銃
Gotta love a souped-up gun!
つけ銃　うめえ…
And when the soup trickles through the rifling... That's good eatin'!
ライフリングに絡むスープがたまらねえ…
Well, it makes my blood run cold.
見てるこっちがひやひやする
That gun's loaded, right?
弾入りだろ　その銃
Don't worry. I'll be careful.
ヘマはしねえっす　ご安心を
And it'll be just fine when it comes to shootin', too.
撃つときにも何の支障もありませんし
I tend to it every night like it's my very own baby boy.
ちゃんと　毎晩　わが子のように手入れしてます
The most delicious gun on any given day is the one that suits me best.
その日一番うまい銃が　その日一番手になじむ
It's kinda like my rule of thumb.
経験則ってやつっすわ　俺の
You're a weird one, all right.
奇特なやつだ　他の２人もそんなんか
Are your two buddies the same way?
Yeah, well...
ええ　まあ
When you've pulled off as many jobs as we have,
俺らみたいに何度も仕事をしてきた連中は
you tend to develop your own little obsessions.
何かしらこだわりが出てくるもんっす
For example, Smog makes all his own poisons.
例えば　スモッグの毒は全て自作
He's so insistent on fine-tuning them for practical use
洗練された実用性にこだわるあまり
that he even made his own lab.
研究室まで作る始末っす
Huh. And the third?
ほう…　では　あと一人　グリップも
What about Grip?
Well...
ええ…
5th Floor Scenic Walkway
CURRENT LOCATION
Even as assassins go, that one's an odd duck.
まあ…　あいつはちょっと　殺し屋の中でも変わってまして…
お…おいおい　めちゃくちゃ堂々と立ってやがる
Hey, why's he just standing out in the open like that?
That vibe he's giving off...
あの雰囲気…
Oh, yeah. I can totally call it now.
ああ　いいかげん見分けがつくようになったわ
When it comes down to it, he's a killer.
どう見ても　やる側の人間だ
A scenic walkway with an unobstructed view!
見通しの良い展望通路
Forget a surprise attack or strength in numbers.
奇襲もできず　数の利も生かせない
Damn it. I wish I had a gun with real bullets.
くっそ…　実弾の銃が欲しい
I never thought I'd need one here on this island.
よもや　この島で必要になるとは思わなかった…
What a drag-eth.
つまらぬ
I can tell-eth from your footsteps that you're not tough enough for me.
足音を聞くかぎり　手ごわいと思える者が一人もおらぬ
And they said some special-forces teacher was tak-eth-ing the lead, too.
精鋭部隊出身の引率の教師もいるはずなのぬ…　だ
I guess Smog's gas must've gotten-eth the better of him.
どうやら　スモッグのガスにやられたようだぬ
Probably killed-eth each other at the same time.
半ば相打ちぬ　といったところかぬ
Come on out, hm.
出てこいぬ
He cracked the window with his bare hand!
手で窓にヒビ入れたぞ
B-But more than that...
そ…それより…
We're all too afraid to say it, but... well...
怖くて誰も言えないけど
何かその…
You sure like adding "eth" to things, buddy!
「ぬ」多くね　おじさん
There it is! Thank goodness for Karma!
言った　よかった　業がいて
「ぬ」をつけると　侍っぽい口調になると小耳に挟んだぬ
I heard it had a cool old-fashioned sound to it, like-eth a samurai.
It's got a cool ring to it, so I'm try-eth-ing it out.
カッコ良さそうだから　試してみたぬ
Oh, so he's a foreigner.
そっか…　外国の人か
I might-eth be doing it wrong, but that's okay.
間違ってるなら　それでもいいぬ
After I kill you all here,
この場の全員　殺してから
I can drop-eth the "eth" and no one will ever know.
「ぬ」を取れば恥にもならぬ
Bare hands... Are those your killing tools, then?
素手…　それがあなたの暗殺道具ですか
My skills are actually in quite high demand, you know-eth.
こう見えて　需要があるぬ
Passing through pat-downs is quite the advantage, after all-eth.
身体検査に引っ掛からぬ利点は大きいぬ
When my prey draws close, I snap-eth their necks.
近づきざま　頸椎を一ひねりぬ
Or if the fancy strikes me, I crush-eth their skulls.
その気になれば　頭蓋骨も握りつぶせるが…
It's funny, you know-eth.
だが　面白いものでぬ
The more you train-eth your strength for the purpose of killing people,
人殺しのための力を鍛えるほど
the more you feel-eth like using it for something other than assassination.
暗殺以外にも試してみたくなるぬ
To be-eth precise, a fight,
すなわち　戦いぬ
to the death, against-eth a mighty foe.
強い敵との殺し合いだぬ
But this is quite-eth the letdown.
だが　がっかりぬ
After seeing who I'm up against,
I've all but lost-eth my will to fight.
お目当てがこのざまでは　試す気もうせたぬ
Not to mention, it's a pain to mop-eth up a bunch of small fry by myself.
雑魚ばかり　１人でやるのも面倒だぬ
I'll call in my boss and my colleague to help-eth out.
ボスと仲間を呼んで皆殺しぬ
Hey, buddy. Chill-eth.
ねえ　おじさんぬ
You seem pretty average for a pro, huh?
意外とプロって普通なんだね
Breaking glass, busting skulls?
ガラスとか頭蓋骨なら　俺でも割れるよ
I can do that much.
But if your opening move is to call in reinforcements,
ていうか　即行　仲間呼んじゃうあたり
I guess that means you're too scared to take on a junior-high kid alone.
中坊とタイマンはるのも怖い人
No! Don't be reckless!
よせ…　無謀だ…
Stop right there, Karasuma-sensei.
ストップです　烏間先生
His chin is down.
顎が引けている
So far he's been showing off his swagger with his chin in the air,
今までの彼なら　余裕をひけらかして
顎を突き出し　相手を見下す構えをしていた
looking down on his opponents.
But this is different.
でも　今は違う
His words may be as rough as ever,
口の悪さは変わりませんが
but his eyes are looking straight ahead, alertly observing his foe head-on.
目は真っすぐ油断なく　正面から相手の姿を観察している
He'd been lying low ever since finals,
テスト以来　少々鳴りを潜めていましたが
but it seems he's learned well from his failures.
どうやら　敗北からしっかり学んだようですね
Very well-eth.
いいだろうぬ
Let's see what you can do-eth.
試してやるぬ
Give this everything you've got.
存分にぶつけなさい
You're facing one high wall: an adult!
高い大人の壁を相手に
太陽が射す　閉ざした瞼の裏側に赤い残像
The sun shines
taiyou ga sasu
On the back of my closed eyelids
tozashita mabuta no uragawa ni
I see red afterimages
akai zanzou
With a notebook and a pen in my leather bag
kawa no kaban ni nooto to pen wo
革の鞄に　ノートとペンを　さあ歩き出そう
I go for a walk
saa arukidasou
I keep drawing, but I can't get it to look pretty
kaitemo kaitemo kirei ni naranai
描いても描いても　綺麗にならない
My choice of colors is not to blame
eranda enogu ni tsumi wa nai
選んだ絵の具に　罪はない
I still remember the shooting star I saw last night
kinou no yonaka ni mita nagareboshi mada oboeteiru
昨日の夜中に見た流れ星　まだ覚えている
I was waiting for...
I was waiting for…
Hello shooting-star Hello shooting-star again
Hello, shooting star
Hello, shooting star, again
I was waiting
matteita yo
待っていたよ
夢を見るあの子はずっと
The girl of many dreams
yume wo miru ano ko wa zutto
ここにいるの　Ah　Ah
Is always here
koko ni iru no
あの日のまま　Ah　Ah
Just like you did that day
ano hi no mama
また光って
Shine again
mata hikatte
左手の６連符に右手の８連符
相容れない二つのリズムが絡み合った時に生まれる息を呑む旋律
それが『幻想即興曲』
どうしたらいい女になれるかって
それならショパンの一つでも弾けなくちゃね　カエデ
次回　暗殺教室　カルマの時間　２時間目